The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Today's lecture is about a brand new data
教授：今天的讲座是关于全新数据的
structure that you've probably seen before,
您之前可能已经看到的结构
and we've mentioned earlier in double 06,
我们之前在双06中提到过
called a binary search tree.
称为二叉搜索树。
We've talked about binary search.
我们已经讨论过二进制搜索。
It's a fundamental divide and conquer paradigm.
这是根本的分而治之范式。
There's a data structure associated with it,
有一个与之相关的数据结构，
called the BST, a binary search tree.
称为BST，即二叉搜索树。
And what I want to do is motivate this data structure
我想做的就是激发这种数据结构
using a problem.
使用问题。
It's a bit of a toy problem, but certainly a problem
这是一个玩具问题，但肯定是一个问题
that you could imagine exists in all sorts
你可以想象各种存在
of scheduling problems.
调度问题。
It's a part of a runway reservation system
这是跑道预定系统的一部分
that you can imagine building.
您可以想象建筑物。
And what I'll do is define this problem
我要做的就是定义这个问题
and talk about how we could possibly solve it with the data
并讨论如何用数据解决它
structures you've already seen-- so lists and arrays, heaps
您已经看到的结构-列表和数组，堆
as well as, which we saw last time--
以及我们上次看到的
and hopefully motivate you into the reason behind the existence
并希望激发您进入存在背后的原因
of binary search trees, because they
二叉搜索树，因为它们
are kind of the perfect data structure
是一种完美的数据结构
for this particular problem.
对于这个特殊的问题。
So let's dive into what the runway reservation system looks
因此，让我们深入了解跑道预定系统的外观
like.
喜欢。
And it's your basic scheduling problem.
这是您的基本计划问题。
We'll assume an airport with a single runway.
我们假设一个机场只有一条跑道。
Now Logan has six runways.
现在，洛根有六个跑道。
But the moment there's any sort of weather you're down to one.
但是，当遇到任何天气时，您都会陷入困境。
And of course, there's lots of airports with a single runway.
当然，很多机场只有一条跑道。
And we can imagine that this runway is pretty busy.
我们可以想象这条跑道非常繁忙。
There's obviously safety issues associated with landing planes,
着陆飞机显然存在安全问题，
and planes taking off.
和飞机起飞。
And so there are constraints associated
因此，存在一些约束条件
with the system, that have to be obeyed.
该系统必须遵守。
And you have to build these constraints in-- and the checks
然后您必须建立这些约束，然后进行检查
for these constraints-- into your data structure.
对于这些约束-进入您的数据结构。
That's sort of the summary of the context.
这就是上下文的摘要。
So reservations for future landings
因此，为将来的着陆保留
is really what this system is built for.
确实是该系统的基础。
There's a notion of time.
有时间观念。
We'll assume that time is continuous.
我们假设时间是连续的。
So it could be represented by a real variable,
因此可以用一个实变量表示
or a real quantity.
或实际数量。
And what we'd like to do is reserve requests for landings.
而我们要做的是保留着陆请求。
And these are going to specify landing time.
这些将指定登陆时间。
Each of them is going to specify a landing time.
他们每个人都将指定登陆时间。
We call it t.
我们称它为t。
And in particular, we're going to add t
特别是，我们将添加
to the set R of landing times if no other landings are scheduled
如果未安排其他降落，则将其降落为设置的降落时间R
within k minutes.
在k分钟内。
And k is a parameter that could vary.
k是可以变化的参数。
I mean, it could be statically set to 3 minutes, or maybe 4.
我的意思是，它可以静态设置为3分钟，也可能是4分钟。
You can imagine it varying it dynamically
您可以想象它会动态变化
depending on weather conditions, things like that.
视天气情况而定。
For the most of the examples we'll talk about today,
对于我们今天要讨论的大多数示例，
we'll assume k is 3 minutes, or something like that.
我们假设k是3分钟，或类似的时间。
So this is about adding to the data structure.
因此，这是关于添加到数据结构中的。
And so an insert operation, if you will,
因此，如果有插入操作，
that has a constraint associated with it that you need to check.
有与之相关的约束，需要检查。
And so you wouldn't insert if the constraint was violated.
因此，如果违反了约束，您将不会插入。
You would if the constraint was satisfied.
如果满足约束，您将愿意。
And time, as I said, is something
正如我所说，时间就是
that is part of the system.
这是系统的一部分。
It needs to be modeled.
它需要建模。
You have the current notion of time.
您拥有当前的时间观念。
And every time you have a plane that's already landed,
每当您有一架已经降落的飞机时，
which means that you can essentially
这意味着您基本上可以
take this particular landing time away
减少这个特殊的着陆时间
from the set R. So this removal, or delete-- we remove
从集合R中删除。因此，删除或删除-我们删除
from set R, which is the set of landing times
从集合R开始，这是着陆时间
after the plane lands.
飞机降落之后。
So every once in awhile, as time increments,
所以每隔一段时间，随着时间的推移，
you're going to be checking the data structure.
您将要检查数据结构。
And you can do this, maybe, every minute, every 30 seconds.
您可以每隔30秒执行一次。
That isn't really important.
那不是很重要。
But you have to be able to remove from this data
但是您必须能够从此数据中删除
structure.
结构体。
So fairly straightforward data structure.
因此，数据结构相当简单。
It's a set, R. We don't quite know how to implement it yet.
这是一个集合，R。我们还不知道如何实现它。
But we'd like to do all of these operations in order log n time,
但是我们想按顺序登录n进行所有这些操作，
where n is the size of the set.
其中n是集合的大小。
All right?
好吧？
So any questions about that?
那么对此有任何疑问吗？
Any questions about the definition
有关定义的任何疑问
of the problem before we move on?
我们继续前进之前的问题？
Are we good on?
我们好吗？
OK.
好。
So let's look at a real straightforward example,
因此，让我们看一个真正简单的示例，
and put this up here so you get a better sense of this.
并将其放在此处，以便您对此有更好的了解。
Let's say that, right now, we are at time 37.
假设现在是37岁。
And the set R has 41.2, 49, and 53 in it.
集合R中有41.2、49和53。
And that's time.
那是时候了。
Now you may get a request for landing time 53.
现在，您可能会收到登陆时间请求53。
And-- I'm sorry.
而且-很抱歉。
I want to call this 56.3-- 41.2, 49, and 56.3.
我想将其称为56.3-41.2、49和56.3。
You may get a request for landing time 53.
您可能会要求登陆时间53。
And right now the time is 37.
现在时间是37。
It's in the future, and you say OK because you've
在将来，您说OK，因为您已经
done the check.
完成了检查。
And let's assume that k equals 3.
并假设k等于3。
And 53 is four ahead of 49, and 3.3 before 56.3, so you're OK.
53比49高4，在56.3之前是3.3，所以您还可以。
44 is not allowed.
不允许44。
It's too close to 41.2.
太接近41.2。
And 20, just for completeness, is not
而20仅仅是为了完整性，不是
allowed because it's passed.
允许，因为已通过。
Can't schedule in the past.
无法安排过去的时间。
I mean, it could be the next day.
我的意思是，可能是第二天。
But then you wouldn't call it 20.
但是那样的话你不会叫20。
Let's assume that time is a monotonically increasing
假设时间在单调增加
function.
功能。
You have a 64-bit number.
您有一个64位数字。
It can go to the end of the world, or 2012,
它可以走到世界末日，也可以是2012年，
or wherever you want.
或您想要的任何地方。
So you can keep the number a bit smaller,
因此，您可以将数字保持较小，
and do a little constant factor optimization, I guess.
我想做一些恒定因子优化。
So that's sort of the set up.
这样就完成了。
And hopefully you get a sense of what the requirements.
希望您对要求有一个了解。
And you guys know about a bunch of data structures already.
你们已经知道了一堆数据结构。
And what I want to do is list each one of them,
我想做的是列出其中每一个，
and essentially shoot them down with respect
并尊重他们
to not being able to make this efficiency requirement.
无法达到此效率要求。
And I'd like you guys to help me shoot them down.
我希望你们能帮助我击落他们。
So let's talk about an easy one first.
因此，让我们先谈一个简单的问题。
Let's say you have an unsorted list or an array corresponding
假设您有一个未排序的列表或对应的数组
to R. That's all you have.
给R。这就是您所拥有的。
What's wrong with this data structure
这个数据结构怎么了
from an efficiency standpoint?
从效率的角度来看？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Pretty much everything you want to do to it is linear.
听众：您要做的几乎所有事情都是线性的。
PROFESSOR: That's exactly right.
教授：完全正确。
Pretty much everything you want to do to it is linear.
您要做的几乎所有事情都是线性的。
And so you want to check the k minute check.
因此，您要检查k分钟检查。
You can certainly insert into it, and just add to it.
您当然可以插入其中，然后添加即可。
So that part is not linear, that's constant time.
所以那部分不是线性的，那是恒定的时间。
But certainly, anything where you
但是可以肯定的是，无论您在哪里
want to go check against other elements of the array,
想去检查数组的其他元素，
it's unsorted.
它是未分类的。
You have no idea of where to find these elements.
您不知道在哪里可以找到这些元素。
You have to scan through the entire array
您必须扫描整个阵列
to check to see whether there's a landing time that's
检查是否有登陆时间
within k of the current time t that you're asking for.
在您要求的当前时间t的k以内。
And that's going to take order n time.
这将需要n次命令。
So you can insert in order 1 without a check.
因此，您可以在不检查的情况下按顺序1插入。
But sadly, the check takes order n time.
但是可悲的是，支票需要n次命令。
All right?
好吧？
Let's do something that is a little more plausible.
让我们做一些看起来更合理的事情。
Let's talk about a sorted array.
让我们谈谈一个排序数组。
So this is a little more subtle question.
因此，这是一个更微妙的问题。
Let's talk about a sorted array.
让我们谈谈一个排序数组。
What happens with a sorted array?
排序数组会怎样？
Someone?
有人吗
What can you do with a sorted array?
您可以对排序数组做什么？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Do a binary search to find the [INAUDIBLE].
听众：进行二进制搜索以找到[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Binary search would find a bad insert.
教授：二进制搜索会发现错误的插入内容。
OK, good.
好好
So that's good.
这样很好。
So if you have a sorted array, and just for argument's sake,
因此，如果您有一个已排序的数组，并且仅出于参数考虑，
it looks like 4, 20, 32, 37, 45.
看起来像是4、20、32、37、45。
And it's increasing order.
而且它在增加顺序。
And if you get a particular time t, you can use binary search.
而且，如果获得特定时间t，则可以使用二进制搜索。
And let's say, in particular, the time is, for example, 34.
具体地说，例如，时间是34。
Then what you do is you go to the midpoint of the array,
然后，您要做的就是转到数组的中点，
and maybe you just look at that.
也许您只是看一下。
And you say oh, 34 is greater than 32.
你说哦，34比32大。
So I'm going to go check and figure out
所以我要去检查一下
if I need to move to the left or the right.
如果我需要向左或向右移动。
And since it's greater I'm going to move to the right.
而且由于它更大，所以我将向右移动。
And within logarithmic time, you'll
在对数时间内，您将
find what we call the insertion point of the sorted array,
找到我们所谓的排序数组的插入点，
where this 34 is supposed to sit.
这34应该坐的地方。
And you don't necessarily get to insert there.
而且您不一定要插入那里。
You need to look, once you've found the insertion point,
找到插入点后，您需要查看一下
to your left and to your right.
在你的左边和右边。
And do the k minute check.
并进行k分钟检查。
So finish up the answer to the question,
因此，完成问题的答案，
tell me how long it's going to take me to find the insertion
告诉我要多长时间才能找到插入内容
point, how long it's going to take me to do the check,
我要花多长时间做支票，
and how long it's going to take me to actually do
我要花多长时间才能真正完成
the insertion.
插入。
AUDIENCE: Log n in the search--
听众：在搜索中登录n-
PROFESSOR: Log n for the search, to find the point.
教授：登录n进行搜索，以找到该点。
AUDIENCE: Constant for the comparison?
听众：比较的常数吗？
PROFESSOR: Constant to the comparison.
教授：一直比较。
And then the last step?
然后最后一步？
AUDIENCE: Do the research [INAUDIBLE].
听众：做研究[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry, little louder.
教授：对不起，大声一点。
Sorry.
抱歉。
AUDIENCE: The insertion is constant.
听众：插入是恒定的。
PROFESSOR: Insertion is constant?
教授：插入是恒定的吗？
Is that right?
那正确吗？
Do you people agree with him, that insertion is constant?
你们是否同意他的观点，即插入是永恒的？
AUDIENCE: You've got a maximum size up there, right?
听众：那里有最大尺寸，对吗？
There must be a maximum.
必须有一个最大值。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: No, the indices-- so right now the array
教授：不，索引-现在是数组
has indices i.
有索引i。
And if you start with 1, it's 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, et cetera.
如果从1开始，则为1、2、3、4、5等。
So what do you mean by insertion?
那么，插入意味着什么？
Someone explain to me what-- yeah, go ahead.
有人向我解释-是的，继续。
AUDIENCE: When you put something in you
听众：当你在里面放东西时
have to shift every element over.
必须转移所有要素。
PROFESSOR: That's exactly right.
教授：完全正确。
That's exactly right.
没错
Ok, good, that's great.
好的，很好。
I guess I should give you half a cushion.
我想我应该给你半垫子。
But I'll do the full one, right?
但是我会做完整的，对吧？
And you get one, too.
你也得到一个。
So the point here is this is pretty close.
因此，这里的重点是非常接近的。
It's almost what we want.
这几乎是我们想要的。
There's a little bit of a glitch here.
这里有一些小故障。
We know about binary search.
我们知道二进制搜索。
The binary search is going to allow us,
二进制搜索将允许我们，
if there's n elements here, to find the place--
如果这里有n个元素，要找到位置-
it's going to be able to find-- and I'm
它将会能够找到-我
going to precise here-- the smallest i such that R of i
这里要精确-最小的i使得i的R
is greater than or equal to t in order log n time.
大于或等于t的顺序登录n次。
It's going to be able to do that.
它将能够做到这一点。
You're going to be able to compare R of i and R of i
您将能够比较i的R和i的R
minus 1-- so the left and the right-- against t
减1-左右-对t
in order 1 time.
以1次。
But sadly, the actual insertion is going to require shifting.
但可悲的是，实际插入将需要移位。
And that could take order n time, because it's an array.
这可能需要n倍的时间，因为它是一个数组。
So that's the problem.
这就是问题所在。
Now you could imagine that you had a sorted list.
现在您可以想象您有一个排序列表。
And you could say, hey if I have a sorted list,
你可能会说，嘿，如果我有一个排序列表，
then the list looks like this, and it's
然后列表看起来像这样，
got a bunch of pointers in it.
里面有一堆指针。
And if I've found the insertion point,
如果我找到了插入点，
then-- the list is nice, because you can insert something
然后-该列表很好，因为您可以插入一些内容
by moving pointers in constant time
通过在恒定时间内移动指针
once you've found the insertion point.
找到插入点后。
But what's the problem with the list?
但是列表有什么问题？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: You can't do binary search [INAUDIBLE].
听众：您无法执行二进制搜索[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Well you can't do binary search on a list.
教授：嗯，您不能对列表进行二进制搜索。
There's no notion of going to the n by 2 index
没有想法去n by 2索引
and doing random access on a conventional list, right?
并在常规列表上进行随机访问，对吗？
So the list does one thing right,
所以这个清单做对了一件事情，
but doesn't do the other thing right.
但没有做正确的另一件事。
The array does a couple things right,
数组可以正确完成几件事，
but doesn't do the shifting right.
但不做右移。
And so you see why we've constructed this toy problem.
因此，您会看到我们为什么构造了这个玩具问题。
It's to motivate the binary search tree data
是为了激发二叉搜索树数据
structure, obviously.
结构，显然。
But you're close, but not quite there.
但是您很亲近，但还不完全到那里。
What about heaps?
那堆呢？
We talked about heaps last time.
我们上次谈到堆。
What's the basic problem with the heap for this problem?
堆的基本问题是什么？
The heaps are data arrays, but you
堆是数据数组，但是你
can visualize them as trees.
可以将它们可视化为树木。
And obviously if we're talking about min heaps and max heaps.
而且很显然，如果我们在谈论最小堆和最大堆。
So in particular, what goes wrong with a min heap or a max
因此，特别是最小堆或最大堆出了什么问题
heap for this problem?
堆这个问题？
What takes a long time?
需要很长时间？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: You have to scan every element, which [INAUDIBLE].
听众：您必须扫描[听不清]的每个元素。
PROFESSOR: That's right.
教授：是的。
I mean, sadly, you know when we talk about min heaps or max
我的意思是，可悲的是，您知道当我们谈论最小堆或最大堆时
heaps, they actually have a fairly weak invariant.
实际上，它们实际上具有相当弱的不变性。
It turns out that-- I'm previewing a bit here--
事实证明-我在这里预览了一下-
binary search trees are obviously
二进制搜索树显然是
similar to heaps in the sense that you visualize
从视觉上讲类似于堆
an array as a tree, in the case of a heap.
如果是堆，则数组作为树。
And binary search trees are trees.
二进制搜索树就是树。
But the invariant in a min heap or a max heap,
但是最小堆或最大堆中的不变量
is this kind of a week invariant.
这种一周不变。
It essentially says, look at the min element.
本质上说，看一下min元素。
And the min element has to be the root,
min元素必须是根，
so you can do that one operation pretty quickly.
因此您可以相当快地完成一项操作。
But if you want to look for a k minute check,
但是，如果您想查看ak分钟检查，
you want to see if there's an element in the heap that
你想看看堆中是否有一个元素
is less than or equal to k, or greater than or equal to k
小于或等于k，或大于或等于k
from t, this is going to take order n time.
从t开始，这将需要n次命令。
OK?
好？
Good.
好。
And finally, we haven't talked about dictionaries,
最后，我们没有谈论字典，
but we will next week.
但是我们下周。
Eric will talk about hash tables and dictionaries.
Eric将讨论哈希表和字典。
And they have the same problem.
他们有同样的问题。
So it's not like dictionaries are going to solve the problem,
所以这不像字典要解决这个问题，
for those of you who know about hash tables and dictionaries.
对于那些了解哈希表和字典的人。
But you'll hear about them in some detail.
但是您会详细了解它们。
They're very good at other things.
他们在其他方面很擅长。
So I don't want to say much more about that, because you're not
所以我不想多说，因为你不是
supposed to know about dictionaries.
应该知道字典。
Or at least we don't want to assume
或者至少我们不想假设
you do, though we have talked about them
你知道，尽管我们已经谈论过
and alluded to dictionaries earlier.
并早些提到字典。
And so that's a story here.
这就是一个故事。
Yeah, back there, question.
是的，回到那里，问。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, can you explain why it's [INAUDIBLE] time?
听众：是的，你能解释为什么现在[听不清]吗？
PROFESSOR: So what is a heap, right?
教授：那是堆，对吗？
A heap essentially-- a min heap, for example,
本质上是一个堆-例如最小堆
or we talked about max heaps last time,
或者我们上次谈到最大堆
has the property that you have an element k,
具有您拥有元素k的属性，
and you're going to look at, let's say it's 21.
您将要看的是21岁。
Let's do min heaps, so this has to be less than what's
让我们做最小堆，所以这必须小于
here, 23, and what there, maybe it's
在这里23岁那边，也许是
30, and so on and so forth.
30，依此类推。
And you have a recursive definition.
并且您有一个递归定义。
And when you insert into a min heap, typically what happens
当您插入最小堆时，通常会发生什么
is suppose you wanted to insert, for argument's sake,
假设您是为了论证而插入
I want to insert 25.
我想插入25。
I want to insert 25 into this.
我想在其中插入25。
The insertion algorithm for a min heap
最小堆的插入算法
typically adds to the end of the min heap.
通常添加到最小堆的末尾。
So what you do is you would add 25 to this.
因此，您要做的是将这加25。
And let's say that you had something out here.
假设您在这里有东西。
So you'd add to it.
所以您要添加它。
And you'd start flipping things.
并且您将开始翻转事物。
And you could work with just this part of the array
您可以只处理阵列的这一部分
to insert 25 in here.
在此处插入25。
And you'd be able to satisfy the invariant of the min heap.
并且您将能够满足最小堆的不变性。
And you'd get a legitimate min heap.
而且您会得到合法的最小堆。
But you'd never check the left part of it, which is 23.
但是您永远都不会检查它的左侧部分，即23。
So it's quite possible-- and this is a good example--
所以这很有可能-这是一个很好的例子-
that your basic insertion algorithm, which is essentially
您的基本插入算法，本质上是
a version of max heap of i, or min heap of i,
i的最大堆或i的最小堆的版本，
would simply insert at the end, and keep
只需在末尾插入，并保持
flipping until you get the min heap property,
翻转直到获得最小堆属性，
would be unable to check for the k minute check
将无法检查k分钟检查
during the insertion.
在插入过程中。
But what you'd have to do is to go look elsewhere.
但是您要做的就是去别处。
That min heap of i we'd never look at--
我永远不会看的那最小的堆-
or the insert algorithm we'd never look at-- and that
或我们永远不会看的插入算法-
would require order n time.
将需要订购n次。
All right?
好吧？
AUDIENCE: Thank you.
听众：谢谢。
PROFESSOR: So that's the story for the min heap.
教授：这就是最小堆的故事。
Thanks for the question.
谢谢你的问题。
And it's similar for dictionaries, as I said.
正如我所说，字典也是如此。
And so we're stuck.
因此，我们陷入困境。
We have no data structure yet that can do all of the things
我们还没有可以做所有事情的数据结构
that I put up on the board to the left, in order log n time.
我把它放在左边的板上，以n次登录。
And as you can see, the sorted array got pretty close.
如您所见，排序后的数组非常接近。
And so if you could just solve this problem,
因此，如果您可以解决这个问题，
if you could do fast insertion-- and by fast I mean order log n
如果您可以进行快速插入-我指的是快速登录log n
time-- into a sorted array, we'd be in business.
时间-按分类排列，我们会做生意。
So that's what we'd like to do with binary search trees.
这就是我们想要对二叉搜索树进行的操作。
Binary search trees are, as you can imagine,
您可以想象，二叉搜索树是
enable binary search.
启用二进制搜索。
But the sorted arrays don't allow fast insertion,
但是排序后的数组不允许快速插入，
but BSTs do.
但是BST可以。
So let me introduce BSTs.
因此，让我介绍一下BST。
As with any data structure, there's
与任何数据结构一样，
a nice invariant associated with BSTs.
与BST相关的一个很好的不变式。
The invariant is stronger than the heap invariant.
不变性比堆不变性强。
And actually, that makes them a different data structure, not
实际上，这使它们成为不同的数据结构，而不是
necessarily a better data structure.
必然是更好的数据结构。
And I'll say why, but different.
我会说为什么，但是有所不同。
For this problem they're better.
对于这个问题，他们会更好。
So one example of a binary search tree looks like this.
因此，二叉搜索树的一个示例如下所示。
And as a binary tree you have a node, and we call it x.
作为二叉树，您有一个节点，我们称其为x。
Each of the nodes has a key of x.
每个节点的密钥为x。
So 30 is the key for this node, 17 for that one, et cetera.
因此，该节点的密钥为30，而那个节点的密钥为17等。
Unlike in a heap, your data structure
与堆不同，您的数据结构
is a little more complicated.
有点复杂。
The heap is simply an array, and you
堆只是一个数组，而你
happen to visualize it as a tree.
碰巧把它想象成一棵树。
The binary search tree is actually
二进制搜索树实际上是
a tree that has pointers, unlike a heap.
与堆不同的具有指针的树。
So it's a more complicated data structure.
因此，这是一个更复杂的数据结构。
You need a few more bytes for every node of the binary search
二进制搜索的每个节点还需要几个字节
tree, as opposed to the heap, which
树，而不是堆，
is simply an array element.
只是一个数组元素。
And the pointers are parent of x.
指针是x的父级。
I haven't bothered showing the arrows here,
我没有打扰在这里显示箭头，
because you could be going upwards or backwards.
因为您可能会向上或向后移动。
And you could imagine that you actually
你可以想象你实际上
have a parent pointer that goes up this way,
有一个向上移动的父指针，
and you have a child pointer that goes this way.
并且您有一个这样的子指针。
So there's really, potentially, three pointers
因此，实际上可能存在三个指针
for each node, the parent, the left child,
对于每个节点，父节点，左子节点，
and the right child.
和合适的孩子
So pretty straightforward.
非常简单。
That's the data structure in terms
这就是数据结构
of what it needs to have so you can operate on it.
它需要什么，以便您可以对其进行操作。
And there's an invariant for a BST.
BST有一个不变性。
What makes a BST is that you have
产生BST的原因是您拥有
an ordering of the key values that
键值的顺序
satisfy the invariant that for all nodes x if y is
满足对于所有节点x的不变量，如果y为
in the left subtree of x, we have--
在x的左子树中，我们有-
if it's in the left subtree then key of y
如果它在左子树中，则y的键
is less than or equal to key of x.
小于或等于x的键。
And if y is in the right subtree we
如果y在正确的子树中，我们
have key of y is greater than or equal to key of x.
y的键大于或等于x的键。
So if we're talking about trees here,
所以，如果我们在这里谈论树木，
subtrees here, everything underneath--
这里的子树，下面的一切-
and that's the stronger part of the invariant in the BST,
这是BST中不变式的更重要部分，
versus in the heap we were just talking about the children.
而不是堆里，我们只是在谈论孩子们。
And so you look at this BST, it is a BST
所以你看这个BST，它是一个BST
because if I look to the right, from the root
因为如果我从根部向右看
I only see values that are greater than 30.
我只看到大于30的值。
And if I look to the left, in the entire subtree,
如果我向左看，在整个子树中，
all the way down I only see values that are less than 30.
一路下跌，我只会看到小于30的值。
And that has to be true for any intermediate node in the tree.
这对于树中的任何中间节点都必须成立。
And the only other nontrivial node here is 17.
而这里唯一的其他重要节点是17。
And you see that 14 is less than 17, and 20 is greater than 17.
您会看到14小于17，而20大于17。
OK?
好？
So that's the BST.
这就是BST。
That's the data structure.
那就是数据结构。
This is the invariant.
这是不变的。
So let's look at why BSTs are a possibility for solving
因此，让我们看一下为什么BST可以解决
our runway reservation problem.
我们的跑道保留问题。
And what I'll do is I'll do the insert.
我要做的就是插入。
So let's start with the nil set of elements,
因此，让我们从零个元素开始，
or null set of elements, R. And let's start inserting.
或空元素集R。让我们开始插入。
So I insert 49.
所以我插入49。
And all I do is make a node that has a key value of 49.
我要做的就是制作一个键值为49的节点。
This one is easy.
这很容易。
Next insert, 79.
接下来插入79。
And what happens here is I have to look at 49,
我要看的是49，
and I compare 79 to 49.
我将79与49进行比较。
And because 79 is greater than 49 I go to the right
因为79比49大，所以我向右移动
and I attach 79 to the right child of 49.
然后我将79附加到49的右子上。
Then I want to insert 46.
然后我要插入46。
And when I want to insert 46 I look at this,
当我想插入46时，我会看这个
I compare 49 and 46.
我比较49和46。
46 is less, so I go to the left side and I put 46 in there.
46较小，所以我转到左侧，然后在其中放46。
Next, let's say I want to insert 41.
接下来，假设我要插入41。
So far I haven't really talked about the k minute checks.
到目前为止，我还没有真正谈论过k分钟检查。
And you could imagine that they're being done.
您可以想象他们正在完成。
I'll show you exactly, or talk about exactly how they're
我会确切地告诉你，或者确切地讲它们的状态
done in a second.
在一秒钟内完成。
It's not that hard.
没那么难。
But let me go ahead and do one more.
但是，让我继续做一遍。
For 41, 41 is less than 49, so I go left.
对于41，41小于49，所以我走了。
41 is less than 46, so I go left and attach it
41小于46，所以我左转到并附加它
to the left child.
给左孩子
All right?
好吧？
So that's what I have right now.
这就是我现在所拥有的。
Now let's talk about the k minute check.
现在让我们谈谈k分钟检查。
It's good to talk about the K minute check
谈论K分钟检查很好
when there's actually a violation.
当实际上有违规行为时。
And let's assume the k equals 3 here.
并假设k等于3。
And so, same thing here.
因此，这里也是一样。
You're essentially doing binary search here.
您实际上是在这里进行二进制搜索。
And you're doing the checks as you're doing the binary search.
就像执行二进制搜索一样，您也在进行检查。
So what you're going to be doing is
所以你要做的是
you're going to check that-- you're going to compare 42
您将要检查-比较42
with 49, with the k minute check.
与49，与K分钟检查。
And you realize they're 7 apart.
您会发现它们相距7。
So that's OK.
这样就可以了
And 42 is less than 49, so you go left.
42小于49，所以您向左走。
And then you compare 42 with 46.
然后将42与46进行比较。
And again, it's less than 46, but it's k away, more than 3
再说一次，它小于46，但是距离k，大于3
away from 46.
远离46。
So that's cool.
太酷了。
And you go left.
然后你走了。
And then you get to 41.
然后达到41。
And you compare 42 with 41.
然后将42与41进行比较。
In this case is greater.
在这种情况下更大。
But it's not k more than it.
但这不比k多。
And so that means that if you didn't have the check,
因此，这意味着如果您没有支票，
you would be putting 42 in here.
您将在此处放入42。
But because you have the check, you fail.
但是因为有支票，所以失败了。
And you say, look, I mean this violates
你说，看，我的意思是这违反了
the safety property, violates the check I need to do.
安全性，违反了我需要做的检查。
And therefore I'm not going to insert--
因此，我不会插入-
I'm not going to reserve a request for you.
我不会为您保留请求。
All right?
好吧？
So what's happened here is it's basically a sorted array,
所以这里发生的基本上是一个排序数组
except that you added a bunch of pointers
除了您添加了一堆指针
associated with the tree.
与树关联。
And so it's somewhere between a sorted list and a sorted array.
因此，它位于排序列表和排序数组之间。
And it does exactly the right thing
它确实做对了
with respect to being able to insert.
关于能够插入。
Once you've found the place to insert,
找到插入位置后，
it's merely attaching this particular new node
它只是附加这个特定的新节点
with it's appropriate key to the pointer.
它是指向指针的适当键。
All right?
好吧？
So what's happened here is that if h
所以这里发生的是
is the height of the tree then insertion
是树的高度然后插入
with or without the check is done in order h time.
有无检查均按h时间进行。
And that's what BSTs are good for.
这就是BST的优点。
People buy that?
人们买那个？
Any questions about how they k minute check proceeded?
关于如何进行分钟检查有任何疑问吗？
Yeah, question.
是的，问题。
AUDIENCE: So, what's it called?
听众：那叫什么？
The what check?
什么检查？
PROFESSOR: The k minute check.
教授：k分钟检查。
Sorry, the k was 3 minutes k.
抱歉，k是3分钟k。
I had this thing over here, add t to the set R
我在这里有东西，将t添加到集合R
if no other landings are scheduled within k minutes.
如果未在k分钟内安排其他降落。
So k was just a number.
所以k只是一个数字。
I want it to be a parameter because it
我希望它是一个参数，因为它
doesn't matter what k is.
不管k是多少。
As long as you know what it is when you do the binary search,
只要您知道二进制搜索的含义，
you can add that in to an argument to your insert,
您可以将其添加到插入的参数中，
and do the check.
并进行检查。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: So in this case, I set k to be 3 out here.
教授：因此，在这种情况下，我将k设置为3。
And I was doing a check to see that the invariant,
我正在检查以确保不变量，
any elements in the BST already, on any nodes that
BST中任何已经存在的任何节点上的元素
had keys that were within 3 minutes--
钥匙在3分钟内-
because I fixed k to be 3-- to the actual time
因为我将k固定为实际时间的3-
that I was trying to insert.
我试图插入的内容。
All right?
好吧？
AUDIENCE: So there's no way [INAUDIBLE].
听众：所以不可能[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: I'm sorry, there's no way?
教授：对不起，没有办法吗？
AUDIENCE: There's no way you could
听众：您不可能
insert the 42 into the tree then?
然后将42插入树中？
PROFESSOR: Well, if the basic insertion
教授：好吧，如果基本的插入
method into a binary search tree doesn't have any constraints.
二进制搜索树中的方法没有任何约束。
But you can certainly augment the insertion method
但是您当然可以增加插入方法
without changing the efficiency of the insertion method.
而不改变插入方法的效率。
So let's say that all you wanted to do
假设您想做的所有事情
was insert into a binary search tree,
被插入到二进制搜索树中，
and it had nothing to do with the runway reservation.
它与跑道保留无关。
Then you would just insert the way I described to you.
然后，您只需插入我向您描述的方式即可。
The beauty of the binary search tree
二进制搜索树的美
is that while you're finding the place to insert,
是，当您找到插入位置时，
you can do these checks-- the k minute checks.
您可以进行这些检查-k分钟检查。
Yeah, question back there.
是的，再问那里。
AUDIENCE: What about 45?
听众：45岁呢？
PROFESSOR: What about 45?
教授：45岁呢？
So this is after-- we haven't inserted 42
所以这是在之后-我们还没有插入42
because it violated the check.
因为它违反了支票。
So when you do 45, then what happens
所以当你做45时，会发生什么
is you see that 45 is less than 49
你看到45小于49
and you pass, because you're more than 3 minutes away.
然后您通过，因为您距离酒店有3分钟多的路程。
We'll stick with that example.
我们将坚持那个例子。
And then you get here and then you
然后你来到这里，然后你
see that 45 is less than 46, and you'd fail right here.
看到45小于46，您将在这里失败。
You would fail right here if you were doing the check,
如果您进行检查，您将在这里失败，
because 45 is not 3 away from 46.
因为45与46之间不是3。
All right?
好吧？
So that's the story.
这就是故事。
And so if you have h being the height of the tree,
因此，如果您将h作为树的高度，
as you can see you're just following a path.
如您所见，您只是在走一条路。
And depending on what the height is
并取决于高度
you're going to do that many operations,
您将要做很多操作，
times some constant factor.
乘以某个恒定因子。
And so you can say that this is order h time.
因此，您可以说这是命令h时间。
All right?
好吧？
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yeah, question back there.
是的，再问那里。
AUDIENCE: In a normal array [INAUDIBLE].
听众：在常规数组中[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Well, it's up to you.
教授：嗯，这取决于您。
In a conventional binary search tree, or the vanilla binary
在常规的二进制搜索树中，或者在原始二进制中
search tree, typically what you're doing
搜索树，通常是您在做什么
is you're doing either find or insert.
您正在查找还是插入。
And so what that means is that you would just
所以这意味着你会
return the pointer associated with that element.
返回与该元素关联的指针。
So if you're looking for find 46, for example, on the tree
因此，如果您要在树上查找46
that I have out there, typically 46 is just the key value.
我在那里，通常46只是关键值。
And there may be a record associated with it.
并且可能有与之相关的记录。
And you would get a pointer to that record
您将获得指向该记录的指针
because it's already in there.
因为它已经在里面了
At that point you can say I want to override.
那时您可以说我要覆盖。
Or if you want, you could have duplicate values.
或者，如果需要，可以有重复的值。
You could have this, what's called a multiset.
您可能有这个，称为多集。
A multiset is a set that has duplicate elements.
多重集是具有重复元素的集合。
In that case, you would need a little more sophistication
在这种情况下，您将需要更多的技巧
to differentiate between two elements that
区分两个元素
have the same key values.
具有相同的键值。
So you'd have to call it 46a and 46b.
因此，您必须将其称为46a和46b。
And you'd have to have some way of differentiating.
而且，您必须采用某种区分方式。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it be a problem
听众：不是问题吗
if the tree's not balanced?
如果树不平衡？
PROFESSOR: Ah, great question.
教授：啊，很好的问题。
Yes, stay tuned.
是的，请继续关注。
So I was careful, right?
所以我很小心，对吗？
I guess I kind of alluded to the fact
我想我暗示了这个事实
that we'd solved the runway reservation system.
我们已经解决了跑道预定系统。
Did I actually say that we'd solved the problem?
我是否真的说过我们已经解决了问题？
Did I say we had solved the problem?
我是说我们已经解决了问题吗？
OK, so I did not lie.
好，所以我没有说谎。
I did not lie.
我没撒谎。
I said that the height of the tree was h.
我说树的高度是h。
And I said that this was accomplished in order h time,
我说这是在h时间内完成的，
right?
对？
Which is not quite what I want, which is really your question.
这不是我想要的，这实际上是您的问题。
So we'll get to that.
这样我们就可以解决。
So we're not quite done yet.
所以我们还没有完成。
But before we do that, it turns out
但是在我们这样做之前，事实证明
that today's lecture is really part one of two.
今天的演讲确实是其中两个的一部分。
You'll get a really good sense of BST operations
您会非常了解BST的操作
in today's lecture.
在今天的演讲中。
But there's going to be a few things that-- we can't cover
但是会有几件事-我们无法涵盖
all of double 6 in the lecture, right?
讲座中双6的全部，对吗？
We'd like to, and let you off for the entire fall,
我们很乐意，让您在整个秋天都放松身心，
but that's not the way it works, all right?
但这不是它的工作方式，好吗？
So it's a great question.
因此，这是一个很好的问题。
I'll answer it towards the end.
我会在最后回答。
I just wanted you to say a little bit
我只是想让你说一点
about other operations.
关于其他操作。
There's many operations that you can do on a binary search
二进制搜索可以执行许多操作
tree, that can be done in order h time,
树，可以按时间顺序完成
and some even in constant time.
甚至在恒定的时间内。
And I'll put these in the notes.
我将其放在便笺中。
Some of these are fairly straightforward.
其中一些非常简单。
Find min can be done in heap, in a min heap.
查找min可以在min堆中的堆中完成。
If you want to find the minimum value, it's constant time.
如果要查找最小值，则为恒定时间。
You just return the root.
您只需返回根。
In the case of a binary search tree, how do you find the min?
在二叉搜索树的情况下，如何找到最小值？
Someone?
有人吗
Worth a cushion.
值得坐垫。
Yep.
是的
AUDIENCE: Keep going to the left?
听众：继续向左走？
PROFESSOR: Keep going to the left.
教授：继续向左走。
And how do you find the max?
以及如何找到最大值？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Keep going to the right.
教授：请继续向右走。
All right great, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
And finally, what complexity is that?
最后，那是什么复杂性？
I sort gave it away, but I want to hear it from you.
我已经把它送走了，但是我想听听你的声音。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Hm?
教授：嗯？
AUDIENCE: It's the height
听众：是高度
PROFESSOR: It's the height, order h.
教授：这是高度，为h。
All right, it's order h complexity.
好吧，这是复杂性的顺序。
Go to the left until you hit a leaf,
向左走直到碰到叶子，
and until leaf order h complexity.
直到叶序h复杂。
Same thing for max.
最大值也一样
And then you can do a bunch of things.
然后您可以做一堆事情。
I'll put these in the notes.
我将这些放在笔记中。
You can find things like next larger
你可以找到下一个更大的东西
x, which is the next largest value beyond x.
x，这是x之外的第二个最大值。
And you look at the key for x and you say, for example,
然后，您查看x的键，然后说，
if you put 46 in there, what's the next thing that's larger
如果您在其中放46，那么下一个更大的东西是什么
and that?
然后？
In this tree here, it's 49.
在这棵树上，它是49。
But that's something which was trivially done in this example.
但这是在此示例中微不足道的。
But in general you can do this in order h time as well.
但一般来说，您也可以按h时间执行此操作。
And you can see the pseudocode.
您会看到伪代码。
And we'll probably cover that in section tomorrow.
我们明天可能会在本节中介绍。
What I want to do today, for the rest of the time I have left,
我今天想做的，剩下的时间，
is actually talk about augmented binary search trees, which
实际上是在谈论增强型二叉搜索树，
are things that can do more and have more data in them
是可以做更多事并拥有更多数据的东西
than just these pointers.
不仅仅是这些指针。
And that's actually something which
这实际上是
should give you a sense of the richness of the binary search
应该让您了解二分查找的丰富性
tree structure, this notion of augmentation.
树状结构，即增强的概念。
And those of you, again, who have taken double 05,
同样，你们中那些拿了双05的人，
you know about design amendments.
您了解设计修正案。
And so specifications never stay the same.
因此规格永远不会保持不变。
I mean, you're working for someone,
我的意思是，您正在为某人工作，
and they never really tell you what they want.
他们从来没有真正告诉你他们想要什么。
They might, but they change their mind.
他们可能会，但是他们改变主意。
So in this case, we're going to change our mind.
因此，在这种情况下，我们将改变主意。
And so we've done this to the extent
因此，我们已经做到这一点
that we can cover all of these in order h time.
我们可以按h时间覆盖所有这些。
And let's say that now the problem specification
假设现在问题规范
changed on us.
改变了我们。
There's an additional requirement
还有一个额外的要求
that we're asked to solve.
我们被要求解决。
And so you sort of committed to BST structures.
因此，您有点致力于BST结构。
But now we have an additional requirement.
但是现在我们还有一个附加要求。
And the new requirement is that we be able to compute rank t.
并且新的要求是我们能够计算等级t。
And rank t is how many planes are
等级t是多少架飞机
scheduled to land at times less than or equal to t.
计划在小于或等于t的时间降落。
So perfectly reasonable question.
那么完全合理的问题。
It wasn't part of the original spec.
它不是原始规范的一部分。
You now have built your BST data structure,
现在，您已经建立了BST数据结构，
you thought you were done.
你以为你完成了。
Sorry, you aren't.
抱歉，您不是。
You've got to do this extra stuff.
您必须要做这些额外的事情。
So that's the notion of augmentation,
这就是增强的概念
which we're going to use this is an example of how we're
我们将要使用的这是我们如何
going to augment the BST structure.
将增强BST结构。
And oh, by the way, I don't want you
哦，顺便说一句，我不要你
to change the complexity from order h.
从订单h更改复杂度。
And we eventually will get to order log n,
我们最终将订购log n，
but don't go change something that was logarithmic to linear.
但不要将对数转换为线性。
That would be bad.
那将是不好的。
So let's talk about how you do this.
因此，让我们谈谈您如何做到这一点。
And I don't think we need this anymore.
而且我认为我们不再需要这个了。
So the first thing we need to do is add a little bit more
所以我们要做的第一件事是增加一些
information to the node structure.
信息到节点结构。
And what we're going to do is augment the BST structure.
我们要做的是增强BST结构。
And we're going to add one little number associated
我们将添加一个关联的小数字
with each node, that looks at the number of nodes below it.
与每个节点一起，查看其下方的节点数。
So in particular, let's say that I
尤其是说
have 49, 46, let's just say 49, 46 for now.
有49、46，现在就说49、46。
And over here I have 79, 64, and 83.
在这里，我有79、64和83。
I'm going to modify-- I'm going to have
我要修改-我要
an extra number associated with each of these nodes.
与这些节点中的每个节点关联的额外数字。
And I'm just going to write that number
我要写那个号码
on the outside of the node.
在节点外部。
And you can just imagine that now the key value has
您可以想象现在关键的价值已经
two numbers associated with it-- the thing
与之相关的两个数字
that I write inside the node, and what I write outside of it.
我在节点内写的内容以及在节点外写的内容。
So in particular, when I do insert or delete
所以特别是当我插入或删除时
I'm going to be modifying these numbers.
我将修改这些数字。
And these are size numbers.
这些是尺寸数字。
And what do I mean by that?
我的意思是什么？
Well these numbers correspond to subtree sizes.
这些数字与子树大小相对应。
So the subtree size here is 1, 1, 1.
所以这里的子树大小是1、1、1
So as I'm building this tree up I'm
所以当我建立这棵树时
going to create an augmented BST structure,
要创建增强的BST结构，
and I've modified insert and delete
并且我已经修改了插入和删除
so they do some extra work.
所以他们做了一些额外的工作。
So let's say, for argument's sake,
所以说，为了争辩，
that I've added this in sort of a bottom up fashion.
我以一种自下而上的方式添加了它。
And what I have are these particular subtree sizes.
我拥有的是这些特定的子树大小。
All of these should make sense.
所有这些都应该是有道理的。
This has just a single node, same thing here.
它只有一个节点，此处相同。
So this subtree sizes associated with these nodes are all 1.
因此，与这些节点关联的子树大小均为1。
The subtree size associated with 79
与79相关的子树大小
is 3, because you're counting 79 and 64 and 83.
是3，因为您要计算的是79、64和83。
And the subtree size associated with 49
并且子树的大小与49相关
is 5, because you're counting everything underneath it.
是5，因为您要计算其下的所有内容。
How did we get these numbers?
我们如何获得这些数字？
Well you want to think about this
好吧，你想想一下
as you started with an empty set,
当您从一个空集开始时，
and you kept inserting into it.
并且您一直插入其中。
And you were doing a sequence of insert and delete operations.
您正在执行一系列插入和删除操作。
And if I explain to you how an insert operation modifies
如果我向您解释插入操作的修改方式
these numbers, that is pretty much all you need.
这些数字，这几乎是您所需要的。
And of course, analogously, for a delete operation.
当然，类似地，用于删除操作。
So what would happen for, let's say you wanted to insert 43?
那么，假设您要插入43会发生什么？
You would insert 43 at this point.
此时您将插入43。
And what you'd do is you follow the insertion path
而您要做的就是遵循插入路径
just like you did before.
就像以前一样
But when you're following that path
但是当你沿着那条路走
you're going to increment the nodes that you're seeing by 1.
您将使看到的节点增加1。
So you're going to add 43 to this.
因此，您将为此添加43。
And you'd add 5 plus 1, because you see 49.
您将加上5加1，因为您看到49。
And then you would go down and you'd see 46.
然后您会下去，看到46。
And so you'd add 1 to that.
因此，您将为此加1。
And then finally, you add 43 and you
最后，您加上43，然后
assign-- since it's a leaf-- you'd
分配-因为它是一片叶子-您会
assign to value corresponding to the subtree size
分配给与子树大小相对应的值
of this new node that you put in there, to be 1.
您放入的这个新节点的值为1。
It guess a little, teensy bit more complicated
猜测有点复杂
when you want to do the k minute check.
当您想进行k分钟检查时。
But from a complexity standpoint,
但是从复杂性的角度来看，
if you're not worried about constant factors,
如果您不担心恒定因素，
you can just say, you know what?
你可以说，你知道吗？
I'm going to first run the regular insert,
我将首先运行常规插入，
ignoring the subtree sizes.
忽略子树大小。
And if it fails, I'm done.
如果失败，我就完成了。
Because I'm not going to modify the BST, and I'm done.
因为我不会修改BST，所以我已经完成了。
I'm not going to have to modify the subtree sizes.
我将不必修改子树的大小。
If it succeeds, then I'm going to go in,
如果成功的话，我要进去，
and I know now that I can increment each of these nodes,
现在我知道我可以增加每个节点，
because I know I'm going to be successful.
因为我知道我会成功的。
So that's sort of a trivial way of solving this problem,
因此，这是解决此问题的一种简单方法，
that from an asymptotic complexity standpoint
从渐进复杂性的角度来看
gives you your order h augmented insert.
给您您的订单h扩大插入。
That make sense?
有道理？
Now you could do something better than that.
现在您可以做得更好。
I mean, I would urge you, if you had wrote something
我的意思是，如果您写了些东西，我会敦促您
that-- we asked you to write something like this,
那-我们要你写这样的东西，
to create a single procedure that essentially uses
创建一个基本上使用
a recursion appropriately to do the right thing in one pass
一次递归以一次完成正确的事情
through the BST.
通过BST。
And we'll talk about things like that
我们将谈论类似的事情
as we go along in sections, and possibly in lectures.
我们会分节进行，甚至可能会在讲座中进行。
So that's the subtree insert delete.
这就是子树插入删除。
Everyone buy that?
每个人都买吗？
Yeah, question back there.
是的，再问那里。
AUDIENCE: If I wanted to delete a number, like let's say 79--
听众：如果我想删除一个数字，比如说79--
PROFESSOR: Yep?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: --would we have to take it out
观众：-我们必须把它拿出来
and then rewrite the entire BST?
然后重写整个BST？
PROFESSOR: What you'd have to do is a bubble up pointers.
教授：您需要做的是使指针冒泡。
So you'd have to actually have 64 connected to-- what
所以您实际上必须连接64个-什么
will happen is 83 would actually come up,
将会发生，实际上是83
and you would essentially have some thing-- this
而且您本质上会有一些东西-这
is not quite how it works-- but 83 would move up
不太正常-但83会上升
and you'd have 64 to the left.
左边有64个
That's what would happened for delete in this case.
这就是在这种情况下要删除的内容。
So you would have to move pointers in the case of delete.
因此，在删除的情况下，您将必须移动指针。
And we're not done with binary search tree operations
而且我们还没有完成二进制搜索树操作
from a standpoint of teaching you about them.
从教给您有关它们的角度来看。
We'll talk about them not just in today's lecture,
我们不仅在今天的演讲中讨论它们，
but later as well.
但后来也一样。
So there's one thing missing here,
所以这里缺少一件事，
though, which is I haven't quite figured out--
不过，我还没有弄清楚-
I've told you how these subtree sizes work.
我已经告诉您这些子树大小如何工作。
But it's not completely clear, this
但这还不是很清楚
is the last thing we have to do, is how are you
是我们要做的最后一件事，你好吗
going to compute rank t from the subtree sizes?
要从子树大小计算等级t？
So everyone understand subtree sizes?
这样每个人都了解子树的大小吗？
It's just the number of nodes that are underneath you.
它只是您下面的节点数。
And you remember to count yourself, all right?
而且您还记得要数一数，好吗？
Now what is rank t?
现在什么是等级t？
Rank t is how many planes are scheduled
等级t是计划的飞机数量
to land at times less than or equal to t.
有时小于或等于t降落。
So now I have a BST structure that looks like the one
所以现在我有了一个BST结构，看起来像一个
and I just ended up with.
我刚结束。
So I've added this 43.
所以我添加了这个43。
And so let me draw that out here,
所以让我在这里画出来
and see if we can answer this question.
看看我们是否可以回答这个问题。
This is a subtle question.
这是一个微妙的问题。
So I got 49, and that subtree size is 6.
所以我得到了49，而子树的大小是6。
I got 46, subtree size is 2.
我得到46，子树大小为2。
43, 79, 64.
43、79、64。
and 83.
和83。
So what I want is what lands before t?
所以我想要的是t之前的降落？
And how do I do that?
我该怎么做？
Give me an algorithm that would allow
给我一个可以允许的算法
me to compute in order h time.
我按顺序计算h时间。
I want to do this in order h time.
我想按小时顺序执行此操作。
What lands before t?
t之前落在什么地方？
Someone?
有人吗
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: So first you would have
听众：所以首先你会
to find where to insert it, like we did before.
像以前一样找到要插入的位置。
PROFESSOR: Right, right.
教授：对，对。
AUDIENCE: And then because we have the order of whatever it
听众：然后因为我们有顺序
was before-- not the order, the--
以前-不是命令-
PROFESSOR: The sizes?
教授：大小？
The sizes?
大小？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: And then we can look what's more than it
听众：然后我们可以看到的不仅仅是它
on the right, we can subtract it and we get--
在右边，我们可以减去它，我们得到-
PROFESSOR: What is more than it on the right.
教授：不仅是右边。
Do you want to say--
你想说-
AUDIENCE: Because, like--
听众：因为，-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: --on the right--
听众：-在右边-
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
AUDIENCE: --and then we can take this minus this
听众：-然后我们可以减去这个
and we get what's left.
我们得到了剩下的。
PROFESSOR: That's great, that's excellent.
教授：太好了，太好了。
Excellent.
优秀的。
So I'm going to do it a little bit differently from what
所以我要做的与做的有点不同
you described.
你描述的。
I'm going to actually do it in a,
我实际上要在一个
sort of, a more positive way, no offense intended.
一种更积极的方式，无意冒犯。
What we're going to do is we're going
我们要做的是
to add up the things that we want to add up.
添加我们要添加的东西。
And what you have to do is walk--
而您要做的就是步行-
your first step was right on.
您的第一步是正确的。
I mean, your answer is correct.
我的意思是，您的答案是正确的。
I'm just going to do it a little bit differently.
我将做一些不同的事情。
You walk down the tree to find the desired time.
您沿着树走下来以找到所需的时间。
This is just your search.
这只是您的搜索。
We know how to do that.
我们知道该怎么做。
As you walk down you add in the nodes that
当您走下时，添加以下节点
is the subtree sizes-- you're just adding in the notes here.
是子树的大小-您只需在此处添加注释。
So if you see-- depending on the number of nodes
因此，如果您看到-取决于节点数
that you see as you're going deeper in,
当您深入时会看到
you want to add in the nodes.
您要添加节点。
And you're going to add one to that, corresponding
然后您将添加一个对应的
to the nodes that are smaller.
到较小的节点。
And we're going to add in the subtree sizes to the left,
我们将在左侧添加子树大小，
as opposed to subtracting.
而不是减去。
That may not make a lot of sense.
那可能没有多大意义。
But I guarantee you it will once we do an example.
但是，我保证你一旦做一个例子就可以。
So what's going on here?
那么这是怎么回事？
I want to find a place to insert.
我想找到一个插入的地方。
I'm not actually going to do the insert.
我实际上不会去做插入。
Think of it is doing a lookup.
想到它正在执行查找。
And along the way, I need to figure out
在此过程中，我需要弄清楚
the less than operator.
小于运算符。
I want to find all of the things that
我想找到所有的东西
are less than this value I'm searching for.
小于我要搜索的值。
And so I have to do a bit of arithmetic.
因此，我必须做一些算术运算。
So let's say that I'm looking for what's
假设我在寻找什么
less than or equal to 79.
小于或等于79。
So t equals 79.
所以t等于79
So I'm going to look at 49.
所以我来看看49。
I'm going to walk down, I'm going to look at 49.
我要走下去，我要看49。
And because I say I'm looking at 49-- and 49
因为我说我在看49和49
is clearly less than 79.
显然小于79。
So I'm going to add 1.
所以我要加1。
And that's this check over here.
这就是这里的检查。
I move on and what I need to do now is move to the right,
我继续前进，现在我需要做的是向右移动，
because 79 is greater than 49.
因为79大于49。
That's how my search would work.
这就是我的搜索工作的方式。
But because I've moved to the right,
但是因为我已经移到右边，
I'm going to add the subtree sizes that were to the left.
我将添加左侧的子树大小。
Because I know that all of the things to the left
因为我知道左边所有的东西
are clearly less than 79.
明显小于79。
So I'm going to add 2, corresponding to a subtree 46.
因此，我将添加2，对应于子树46。
So I'm not actually looking there.
所以我实际上不在那儿。
But I'm going to add all of that stuff in.
但我要添加所有这些内容。
I'm going to move to the right, and now I'm going to see 79.
我将向右移动，现在将看到79。
At this point 79 is less than or equal to 79.
在这一点上，79小于或等于79。
So I'm going to see 79 and I'm going to add 1.
所以我将看到79并添加1。
And because I've added 79, just like I did with 49,
而且因为我添加了79，就像我添加49一样，
I have to add the subtree size to the left of 79.
我必须将子树大小添加到79的左侧。
So the final addition is I add 1 corresponding
所以最后的加法是我加1对应
to the subtree 64.
到子树64。
And at this point I've discovered
至此，我发现
where I have to insert, I've essentially found the location,
我必须在其中插入的位置基本上已经找到了位置，
it matches 79.
它匹配79。
And there was no modification required in this algorithm.
而且该算法不需要修改。
So if that was 78 you'd essentially do the same things.
因此，如果那是78岁，您基本上会做同样的事情。
But you're done because you found the value, or the place
但是您完成了，因为您找到了价值或地点
that you want to insert.
您要插入的内容。
And you've done a bunch of additions.
您已经做了很多补充。
And you go look at add 1, add 2, add 1, add 1, and you have 5.
然后看一下添加1，添加2，添加1，添加1，然后得到5。
And that's the correct answer, as you
那是正确的答案，就像你
can see from this example.
从这个例子可以看出。
So what's the bad news?
那么什么是坏消息呢？
The bad news was what this lady said up
坏消息是这位女士说的
front, which was we haven't quite solved the problem.
前面，那是我们还没有完全解决问题。
Because sadly, I could easily set things
因为可悲的是，我可以轻松地设置东西
up such that the height h is order n, h could be order n.
使得高度h为n阶，h可以为n阶。
And if, for example, I gave you a sorted list,
例如，如果我给您一个排序列表，
and I said insert into binary search tree
我说插入二进制搜索树
that's originally null 43, and you put 43 in there.
那原来是零值43，然后您在其中放了43。
Then I say insert 46.
然后我说插入46。
And then I say instead of 48.
然后我说而不是48。
And then I say insert 49, et cetera.
然后我说插入49，等等。
And, you know, these could be any numbers.
而且，您知道，这些可以是任何数字。
Then you see that what does this look like?
然后您会看到这是什么样子？
Does it look like a tree?
它看起来像一棵树吗？
It looks like a list.
它看起来像一个列表。
That's the bad news.
那是坏消息。
And I'll let Eric give you good news next week.
下周，我会让埃里克给您个好消息。
We need to have this notion of balanced binary search trees.
我们需要具有平衡二进制搜索树的概念。
So everything I've said is true.
所以我说的都是真的。
I did not lie.
我没撒谎。
But the one extra thing is we need
但还有一件事是我们需要
to make sure these trees are balanced so h is order log n.
确保这些树是平衡的，因此h是命令log n。
And then everything I said works.
然后我所说的一切都奏效。
All right?
好吧？
See you next time.
下次见。